#### **Devin Halladay**

Multidisciplinary designer 440-409-2114 devin@devinhalladay.com

#### INTRODUCTION

My name is Devin Halladay, and I'm a designer with an affinity toward product design, user experience, typography, print, and branding and identity.

I live and work according to four core tenets: learn the rules, break them with spirit and intent, experiment relentlessly, and create intelligently.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's of Fine Arts Candidate in Graphic Design and Interdisciplinary Sculpture, Maryland Institute College of Art, Expected Graduation May 2019

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Designer, Freelance 2012-Present

Working with a wide range of clients on diverse projects including product and web design, UX design, branding and identity, poster design, and print has given me the opportunity to explore the design landscape freely. I collaborate with developers, designers, and business owners to create effective solutions for clients small and large, in the technology, communications, fashion, lifestyle, entertainment, financial tech, and non-profit industries.

# Developer/Open Source Maintainer, Spotio 2016

I spent two weeks reverse engineering and re-skinning Spotify's Mac app to create Spotio, which now has thousands of global users, was featured on the front page of The Verge, Engadget, and The Next Web, and is popular on Github with over 300 stars and over 25 forks.

# Designer/Founder, Ministry of Print 2014-2015

As an experiment and successful side project, the Ministry of Print worked to design posters revolving around the connection of word and visual, concept and creation, ephemeral and enduring. Experimentations in communication and representation allowed me to freely break my own rules, fail, and succeed through a process of intellectual ideation and the physical graphic manifestation of my thought processes.

### Designer, Leapwise 2014-2015

At Leapwise my job was to create a wide range of designs for clients, ranging from nonprofits to startups to corporations. I worked closely with a team of three other designers and a developer to create effective solutions to client briefs. Additionally, I collaborated daily with the team of developers at Veritix, a Cleveland-based ticketing solutions company, to design and execute a line of ticketing apps and a conceptual rebrand of the company itself and its flagship product, FlashSeats.

### **SELECTED WORKS & WRITING**

Portfolio & Writing: devinhalladay.com Dribbble: dribbble.com/devinhalladay Github: github.com/devinhalladay Behance: behance.com/devinhalladay

#### **LEADERSHIP**

# Leader, MICA Design League 2015-Present

As a freshman, I was invited to lead the MICA Design League, a student-run organization backed by the GD department. MDL sponsors and organizes exhibitions, events, and programming for the department. Responsibilities include organizing meetings and events, meeting with advisors, and leading trips. The nomination made me the first freshman ever to lead the MDL.

### AWARDS, EXHIBITIONS, & PUBLICATIONS

2016	Piece featured in the MICA Photography department's
	juried exhibition Photography: The Form

- 2016 Two pieces featured in the MICA Graphic Design Department's exhibition *System, Process, Context* in the Bronze Gallery.
- 2016 Spotio, my open-source Rdio-inspired theme for Spotify, had 5,000 users one day after launch and was featured by *The Verge*, *Engadget*, *The Next Web*, and international tech reporting websites.
- 2016 Two pieces selected to be featured in I Invited Britney Spears To Dinner (The Invitation Was Not Accepted), a multidisciplinary graphic design exhibition.
- 2016 Recipient of the Louise N. Myerberg Family Competitive Scholarship
- 2016 Two magazines selected by jury to be featured in MICA's Fall Foundation Show in the fall of 2016.
- 2016 Featured as an outstanding underclassman in MICA's quarterly magazine, *Juxtapositions*.
- 2016 Synesthesia poster featured in MICA Design League's Shhhow!, an exhibition in MICA's Brown Center.
- 2015 Recipient of scholarships including the Trustee Scholarship, Fanny B Thalheimer Scholarship, and Creative Vision Award.
- 2015 Ministry of Print website featured on Typewolf, Betalist, Product Hunt, and Hacker News

### SKILLS

Writing
Analysis & Design Criticism
Mobile & web product design
User experience design
Frontend development
Print design
Typography